Well, it's good to see everybody um
virtually. I wish you guys could have
been here. Um but nonetheless, just
really excited with what we were able to
accomplish uh this week in free agency.
Well, at least the start of free agency.
Um as you guys know, free agency never
ends from from here on out. There's
there's going to be ways in which we can
acquire players a little bit down the
road. um obviously through free agency
but also through uh the draft uh
potential trades and through the cut
down process. So um it's just the
beginning but excited with what we were
able to do. We really went into this
free agency uh looking to elevate our
floor right um adding depth pieces but
also players that have had starting
experience that could that can start and
that have shown that they're able to
start in this league. So, uh, for one
way or the other, maybe, um, injuries
may have hurt them, uh, throughout their
careers or recently, um, or other
methods, but, you know, we're happy that
we were able to get the players that we
were able to to acquire, uh, the last
few days. Um, you know, we were really
looking for value across across uh
across the fronts and throughout the um
the roster. And what we did was we
really wanted to find alignment right
within our coaching staff, within our
personnel staff, and also uh within our
analytics. So, um our our scouts did a
really good job of really setting the
table, providing our coaches players to
evaluate, uh providing our analytics
crew, players to look at, and we really
searched for alignment across all three
fronts and feel like we we found a good
band of players to really target and
really happy with how we came out of
this um this week so far. So, a lot of
thank yous go out to everybody involved,
the whole football operation, uh, from
the cafeteria for some of these visits
to our operation staff bringing the
players and their families in. Um, but
also, you know, the the people upstairs,
right? So, just want to say thank you
there. And then, you know, the last few
days been locked in a room uh with Matt,
with um Kevin in and out, uh, but really
our our our CAP crew, right? and uh got
a chance to really spend some quality
time with them these last few days and
and couldn't thank uh Chris Olsen, Karen
Jones, and and Kevin Wiseman enough for
for their support within the
negotiations and everything um these
last few days. Um obviously we're we're
aware of the the the most recent um
articles and things that have come out
regarding James Pierce. Um you know,
those are those are concerning, right,
to to say the least. Um, but outside of
that, um, I'll just keep it just very
similar to what we said at the combine.
You know, we're not going to comment,
uh, on an open legal matter, uh, here
moving forward. So, with that, uh, we'll
open up for questions.
>> Mark Randi.
>> Hey, how are you?
>> Hey, Mark.
>> Just wanted to ask you about, uh, it
seems like a lot of the signings have
been one-year deals, some two-year
deals. How important is is the
flexibility, the cap flexibility, the
you know the the length flexibility that
you guys are looking for right now?
>> Yeah, that's very important. Um, you
know, giving guys a chance to to come
here, compete, uh, play meaningful
snaps, uh, to potentially help them in
their career, but, you know, also most
importantly, help us this season, right?
Um, that that definitely went into to
some of the decision-m and and quite
frankly, just the limited cap space that
we had. we had to be strategic with with
some of those moves.
>> And if I can just ask one more, is there
is there anyone uh any signing in
particular that you feel like has, you
know, a really high upside that that
you're excited about? I don't want to,
you know, make you kind of make one
person stand out over another, but is
there anything that you say, "Okay, I'm
I'm really glad that we got this guy at
this value."
>> Yeah, there's I'd say a lot of these
guys, man. Um, I know I'm just not going
to single out any one, but the value
that we were able to get the players,
uh, the 12 players that we brought in
and, you know, being able to get Leo
back, um, feel really good about that
and their opportunity to come in here,
compete and help us this year and and
help their, you know, themselves out in
their future.
>> Zach Klein,
>> hey, um, what what did you tell Tua in
terms of competing for the starting job?
Is he your backup or will he have a
chance to earn QB1?
>> Yeah. Uh, Zach, you know, it's funny,
you know, Kevin mentioned this in in
February. We're not in the business of
really um handing out starting positions
and in February and, you know, in March
the same, right? Um, for Tua coming in
here, he knows he's coming in to compete
just like Michael knows that he's coming
in to compete. And everybody, quite
frankly, not just those two at the
quarterback position, but everybody's
coming in to compete. Um, there's no
starters right now. And um you know,
we're excited to have Tua, but we're
excited to have all the players that we
were able to get this free agent class.
>> Go to home team.
>> Ian, thanks for the time. uh when you
look at uh what you've done so far, uh
what do you say to the fans about uh the
alignment that you talked about and
getting veterans in, but also preparing
for the future uh with the draft coming
up and where do you think you are with
the alignment of players that fit right
now, but also trying to better the team?
>> Yeah, really excited. Really excited. Um
you know, we've had some really good
conversations across all departments. um
had a free agent meeting last Friday to
to kind of rehash what the coaches views
are of the players that we were trying
to acquire. A lot of which we brought in
this week. Um so there there was
alignment across the board like I stated
earlier um throughout you know the
coaching staff personnel but also
through analytics. Um so really excited
about that. you know, earlier this week,
you know, sat in Brick's office, had a
conversation with him, just making sure
that we were on the same page with what
he was looking for, particularly um
across the defensive front and
linebackers. Again, it's just constant
communication, right? And and anything I
think those are that's what helps all of
us. And for the for the fans, I'm
excited. You know, we all are excited.
We feel like we got better this week.
Um, like I said, we've elevated our
floor, but we've also got players that
are coming in here ready to prove
themselves to showcase their ability um
and and help our team for the now and
and and in the future.
>> And also, as a followup, what holes do
you believe you've actually filled and
what holes do you still need to be
filled in your opinion as you approach
the draft?
>> Yeah, I just I I I personally still feel
a little bit uncomfortable, right? It's
and again, I've got to continue to tell
myself the same thing. It's it's only
March, right? Um and we've got uh
different ways to acquire players. Um
we're not playing a game tomorrow, but I
told our crew, you know, we're not
playing a game tomorrow, but we have to
have the urgency like we have a game
tomorrow, right? So, um it's just
constantly trying to make sure that we
have um we we're bringing in players
that fit what the coaches are looking
for and fit what we're about in terms of
the culture.
>> Josh Kendall
Good morning. And I'm wonder if you
could, as specific as you're willing to
go, how did the analytics team fit into
all this? Was this sort of projecting
based on these guys careers where
they're going or based on how their play
style fits into what you think y'all are
going to do?
>> Um, you know, our our our analysts crew
is is is awesome. Uh, they they help
with a lot of the decision- making. um
they've have models that they put
together uh for things that matter to to
them obviously in their space but also
matter to us and we try to do our best
to align um the grades right across our
personnel staff, our coaching staff and
our analytics. So really just trying to
find where we're in alignment um from
their viewpoint, from the coaches
viewpoint and from uh personnel.
>> Thank you. home team.
>> Ian, Ian, how do you value the um uh the
backup running back position now that
Tyler has moved on? He and Bejon were a
pretty good one-two punch. Uh what are
your thoughts on just the value of the
depth chart as it as it changes now for
you guys at the running back position?
>> Yeah, we've we've got two uh two backups
right now and we're going to add to
those, you know, throughout the process.
Um, and we'll see and we'll evaluate uh
the rest of the free agency, the free
agent market. Um, the draft is coming up
as well. There's going to be some good
backs in the draft. Uh, and then again,
like like I stated earlier, free agency
never ends. There's other ways to
acquire players uh throughout the summer
and and cut down. So, we'll continue to
to look at that market and and there
will be additions to the running back
room.
>> Thank you,
>> Josh. Tend.
Did you guys I don't know how y'all
handle this. I just don't know how it
works. Did you guys talk to Michael
before the Penn edi before the TU
edition and say this is what we're
doing. This is our thought process. Or
do you feel like that needs to happen or
is it just the same as you're bringing
in another defensive tackle? This is
what we do.
>> Yeah, good good question, Josh. Um, you
know, how we do everything, man. It's
it's um yes, to answer your question,
yes, you talked to him. Kevin Kevin
talked to him. I talked to his agent uh
when we knew that this was the the
direction we're going. It's just again
you just want to you don't want to
blindside somebody. Um and that's just
how we operate, right? Uh we want to
have open conversations and
communication and feel like we we did
that uh with in regards to Michael and
Tua
>> Jim.
Ian, did you talk to Matt Ryan about Tua
and uh overall what's the position about
the opportunity to have two guys maybe
compete for the job?
>> Yeah, Matt and I talk uh constantly
throughout the day uh as well as Kevin.
So, those conversations, not just with
Tua, but every everything. Um um we had
some some long nights and some fun
conversations. Um it's brought us closer
together. It's brought Kevin, all three
of us closer together. So again, we're
all on the same page. We're all in
alignment. Um and and uh it's been fun
to have those guys uh in your corner and
and in your foxhole and um you know,
building this thing together.
>> Zack Klein.
>> Yeah. Just kind of a big picture
question now that you're you know in the
hot seat running this show, Ian. the
timing of everything. Do do you think,
you know, in terms of guys getting in
physical, we saw what happened with
Baltimore, you know, do you think this
free agent process should be maybe moved
a little bit later to give you guys more
time to focus on the draft and maybe put
after the draft if you had your say?
>> You know, I haven't thought about in
terms of be uh after the draft. Uh but,
you know, those the the physicals are a
big part of this, right? And um those
are conversations that we'll we'll have
moving forward, but um it's unfortunate,
you know, when some of those things
happen. Um you know, we're going through
it right now just in terms of getting
our guys physicals and making sure that
they're healthy and uh we can we can
sign them to our to the deals that we
agreed upon. But I do think that we may
have to change or tweak some things just
to help so you don't have some of those
big uh like situations come up. But
those are conversations that we'll think
of moving forward. I'm still getting
used to just being in the seat like you
said, the hot seat.
>> And just a quick followup. Um, obviously
Tu has had some issues in the past. Um,
everything good on that and on that
front when you guys looked at evaluating
him?
>> Yeah, just in in terms of evaluating the
player, everything is good there. But,
uh, he's still going through all that
process here this morning. So, we'll
find out here shortly.
>> Josh, did you have another one?
Yeah. Um, just wanted to ask about Chris
Williams and Lale London. What why do
they fit what you want to do up front
defensively? And do you feel like that's
an area where you're not done? I know
you don't feel done anywhere, but is
defensive line particularly an area
where you'd like to add more folks?
>> Yeah, you know, it's it's not what what
I want to do, it's what the what the
coaches want to do, right? And just
that's why I feel like those it's really
important to be in alignment and have
that that communication and transparency
across you know all coaches but
especially with Brick and and Nate and
Teimu and those guys. Um, you know, what
Lale brings is is a like he had a really
good year last year, you know, uh, with
five sacks, I believe, and helped this
defense and and and made an impact um,
on on the defense and in the locker
room. And getting a guy like Chris
Williams, who I'm familiar with, who
Kevin's familiar with from his time in
Cleveland, it gives you an athletic uh
defensive tackle that, you know, fits uh
what the attacking front, what Brick
wants, you know, to be able to get up
field, plan his foot, change direction,
run and chase to the red line. You know,
he's capable of doing all those things
that they're looking for. So excited
about Lale, excited about Chris, but
also excited about adding adding to that
room moving forward.
a home team.
>> Ian, what what is your opinion or
concern? Maybe uh Michael Penn has had a
unique uh really unique uh journey to
start his NFL career about maybe looking
over his shoulder. Uh if there's a
competition situation now that an
accomplished quarterback is in the
building,
>> um I feel like Mike's going to come in
here and compete just like he always
does. Everybody's going to come in here
and compete, right? That's what our job
is to do is to bring in players that fit
uh what our coaches want to do
schematically that fit, you know, Brick
says they rep our style. Um so bring
that brand uh to the locker room and to
the field and they're going to go out
here and compete. So outside of Michael,
it's it's everybody, right? So I'm
looking forward to just seeing how the
team competes and u here moving forward.
>> Got time for a couple more. Zach Klein.
>> And when you and I were talking in Indie
and you said asked you about the Georgia
Bulldogs, you're like, "Yeah, you know,
they they got it right in the program
and uh what a couple weeks later we see
Channing and Aziz. What do you see in
those two gentlemen and what do they
bring to your squad?"
>> Yeah, it wasn't it wasn't intentional.
It's they're good players, right? Um you
know, with Aziz, you know, I want to say
he broke the the rookie sack record for
the Giants. Um you know, evaluated him
since his time at Georgia. You know,
he's had he's had production throughout
his career. I think for him and he he'd
like to I'm sure he would say, you know,
last year didn't go the as as planned,
but this is a guy that plays our brand,
right? He he plays hard. He's physical.
He's got some rush. He's got long arms.
Um he plays with uh the tenacity that
we're looking for and and Channing
Tindle is he's had production on special
teams throughout his career at Georgia.
He was a really good special teams
player. He showcased that, you know,
last year as well. Um it gives us a
player that fits um what Brick looks for
in linebackers in terms of the height,
weight, speed, but also gives them a
chance to come in here and compete for a
spot.
>> We'll finish up with Josh Kendall.
Hey Ian, this is a a Jan Dodson question
and kind of what you liked about Jan
Dodson, but more broadly, I I wonder
what you remember of him coming out and
when you see a guy who's got that kind
of pedigree, a firstround talent and it
doesn't necessarily click, I wonder as a
scout if you sort of keep particular
eyes on those types of guys around the
league and think, you know, maybe
there's a value there, maybe there's
some untapped potential there that we
saw coming out of Penn date and now we
feel like it's now is the right time to
see if he's arrived.
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I feel like it it's
it's clicked. You know, you've seen
you've seen it flicker and and flashes
throughout his career. U you know,
coming out of Penn State, obviously the
the like you just hit on just what he
was able to do there. Um, but he also
was a punt returner. He had some dynamic
pay uh plays. Uh the speed, you know,
jumps off the tape. So you saw that
earlier in his career in Washington as
well. You know, he had production in
Washington and a new regime comes in and
I believe uh they traded him to to
Philadelphia and then you go and you
play uh in that offense behind some some
good players as well. So it gives I feel
like bringing him here it gives him a
chance to showcase uh what he's capable
of doing and what he was uh kind of
building up to in his time in Washington
and it fits our offense. Uh, it
compliments Drake, compliments uh,
Bejon, and and also compliments Kyle. So
excited for what he's capable of doing,
excited for him getting a chance to to
showcase what he's capable of doing. And
not just him, but OZ and, um, a lot of
the other guys that we brought in. So,
um, excited about those additions and
excited about what we're able to do, uh,
here moving forward too.
>> All right. Thank you everybody.
>> Thanks, man. Good seeing you guys.